回你波斯顿老家前.
I still think we should call first...
还是先打个电话过去吧
before we go all the way to Boston to see your folks.
杰森，他们会不让我们去的
Jason, they'd just tell us not to come.
爸爸，让我来帮你们拿
Oh, here, let me. I'll get those for you, Dad.
凯罗，亲爱的，我们要走了
Carol, honey, we're almost ready.
你在跟我说话吗？
Were you speaking to me?
怎么行程安排一直没告诉我
No one spoke to me when this trip was being planned.
我们也是昨晚才知道的
Honey, we didn't know we were going until last night.
凯罗，我们很担心外公外婆
Carol, we're worried about Grandma and Grandpa.
麦姬，你过虑了
Oh, Maggie, I think you're overreacting.
他们干嘛临时取消来访？
Then why did they call and cancel their trip at the last minute?
爸爸干嘛说“一切安好”
And why did my dad say everything was "swell"?
因为一切安好？
Because it is?
不，我爸从来不说“安好” “妥当”，“不错”这些词
No, Jason. My father doesn't use words like "swell," "good," or "nice."
有我在场时从来不说
Certainly not when I'm in the room.
走吧!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
本，很兴奋？
Well, you sure are excited about this, Ben.
是啊，外公会让我玩他的警棍.
Are you kidding? Grandpa's gonna let me use his nightstick...
手铐，甚至警章
and his handcuffs, and even wear his badge.
也会还会让你打手印
Hey, maybe you'll get fingerprinted, too.
太棒了!
Wow!
爸，再次谢谢你让我留在家.
Well, Dad, again, I just want to thank you for letting me stay home...
帮萨克先生的草坪施肥赚点零用钱
and earn some extra money helping Mr. Sacks fertilize his lawn.
赚钱能让我知道钱的价值
I'm sure that earning money will teach me a new respect for the dollar...
让我长大成人
and help me grow as a person.
施肥你确实很在行
Bet you'll be pretty good at spreading manure, too.
可惜不能在外婆的钢琴伴奏下唱歌
And I'm so sorry that I'm going to miss that sing-along around Grandma's piano.
是啊
Yeah.
记住，若是碰上麻烦.
Well, just remember, if you have any problems here...
打电话给隔壁的库斯曼家
you call the Koosmans next door.
今晚不许留宿多过一个人
And only one guest stays over tonight.
太不公道了
This is not fair.
没有人在乎凯罗还有别的事情
No one thought that old Carol might have other plans.
屋子里没一个人.
No one in this entire house...
把我当作是一个活生生的人
treated me like a real, living, breathing human person.
凯罗，上车
Carol, get in the car.
宝贝，再见
Bye, sweetheart.
麦克，这里会一切安好
Oh, and, Mike, I know everything will be fine, because if it isn't...
不然我把你关到35岁
you'll be grounded until you're 35.
够了够了
Enough said.
-爸妈，再见 -麦克，明天见
- Bye, Mom. Bye, Dad. - See you tomorrow, Mike.
玩得开心点，再见
All right. Have fun. Bye-bye.
太好了!
Yes!
(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E20 -= Be.A.Man =- Subripped by zerox
-本，等等我们 -我要上厕所
- Ben, wait for us. - I got to go to the bathroom.
我们一起给外公外婆惊喜
We want to surprise Grandma and Grandpa together.
若外公现在搜我身.
If Grandpa starts frisking me before I go...
我就会让他惊喜
I'll surprise him, all right.
-嗨 -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
我是埃德和凯特的女儿麦姬
I'm Ed and Kate's daughter, Maggie.
好，失陪了
Good. Excuse us, please.
你们就这么走进去吗？
Should you just walk in there like that?
难道要敲门.
What, we should knock and stand out here in the cold...
然后站在寒风中等人来开门
waiting for some jerk to open the door?
进来吧
Come on.
什么人？
Who are they?
妈妈，这些就是圣诞节不送卡片的亲戚？
Mom, are these people the relatives you don't send Christmas cards to?
我要去找外公外婆
I'm going to try to find Grandma and Grandpa.
你们好，快进来
Oh! How are you folks? Come on in.
行李也带来了？
I see you brought your luggage.
别着急，入夜前就能买下来
Well, don't worry, we'll try to close this deal by nightfall.
孩子也带来了，太好了 吃热狗吗？
The kiddies, too. This is so nice. Cocktail frank?
我不吃狗
My name's not Frank.
-你是谁？ -我是谁？
- Who are you? - Who am I?
我不认识你，也不认识这些人
I don't know you. I don't know him.
我是梦幻房地产的哈里
Harry Bittle. Great American Dream Realty Company.
-这房子要卖掉？ -是的
- This house is for sale? - Yes.
房主在哪？
Where are the owners?
房主未曾露面
Oh, well, the sellers are never present for the showing.
住了30年，有感情
Especially sellers who have put 30 years into a place.
-倒是会触景生情 -是的
- This would break their heart. - I'm sure.
-现在还没有买主 -你们对房子有兴趣？
- Well, honey, they haven't sold it yet. - You folks are interested in this house?
当然了
Deeply.
让我指出这栋古色古香的房子的优点
Oh. Well, then let me point out some of the fine features of this timeless classic.
-别说了，我要哭了 -什么？
- If you do, I'm going to cry. - Pardon?
为什么要卖？
Why are they selling?
不想听听关于房子的事？
You're not interested in hearing about the house?
我爱这栋房子
I love this house.
我就在这个火炉旁做功课 等爸爸下班回来.
I'd do my homework right by the fireplace, waiting for my daddy to come home...
放下枪，给我一个拥抱
and hang up his gun and give me a hug.
房主为什么要卖？
Why are they selling?
这是保密的
Well, I can't really violate their confidence.
可以说是.
But I will say, retirement income...
退休金泡汤
balloon payment, disaster.
-没事，我是她的心理医生 -能效劳吗？
- It's all right. I'm her psychiatrist. - Well, can I do anything?
请让我们单独一阵子，谢谢
Yes, you could just give us a moment alone, please. Thank you.
麦姬，甜心，我们去弄个清楚
Come on, Maggie, sweetheart, come on, we'll look into this.
要卖掉房子肯定很难受
Selling this house has to be breaking their hearts.
我知道，但为什么不找我们帮忙？
I know. Why didn't they come to us for help?
爸爸自尊心强
Oh, my father's pride.
他怎么会跟我们要钱.
There is no way he could ask us for money, knowing...
尤其他又这样看待你的工作
the way he feels about what you do for a living.
-什么？ -没什么
- What? - Forget I said that.
我知道他不喜欢我 想不到也不喜欢我的职业
I knew he didn't care for me. I didn't think he hated my entire profession.
他不是讨厌你的职业
Oh, honey, it's not that he hates your profession.
他只是不了解
It's just that he doesn't know what it is.
Oh.
17年了，现在才告诉我？
So now, after 17 years, I find this out?
他以为你只是个江湖郎中，所以.
Now, what good would it have done to let you know that he thinks you're a quack?
江湖郎中？
A quack?
杰森，这个以后再谈吧
Jason, can we talk about this later?
见到二老前 我不希望房子已经被卖掉
Now, I don't want this house sold until we get a chance to talk to Mom and Dad.
好的
Sure, sure.
原木制造，塑料密钉花边
Genuine lath and plaster on real two-by-four studs.
不好意思，打断一下.
Excuse me. I don't mean to interrupt, Harry...
说吧
No problem.
刚才你的话我没听明白
What you were saying over there confused me.
尸体是在这里还是那边的房间里发现的？
Were the victims' bodies found in this room or all through the house?
-这才叫做人生 -麦克!
- This is life as it should be. - Mike!
麦克!
Mike!
太棒了
Man, that was good.
大伙也来得太早了
Guys, how you doing? You're early.
比萨饼还没订呢
I didn't even order the pizza yet.
我去吧，我表哥在店里，会有折扣
Let me do it. My cousin Gus works for Paradise Pizza. I can get us a discount.
-好吧 -今晚有何安排？
- All right. - So, Mikey, what's the action?
随便吧，吃比萨，看电视
Not much. Not much. We're gonna eat a little pizza, watch a little TV.
看电视？麦克，家里又没人!
TV? Mike, your folks ain't home.
千载难逢的机会就看电视？
This is, like, the chance of a lifetime, and you wanna watch TV?
节目已经开始了
It's already started.
麦克，你怎么.
Mike, what could be so important that...
哇!
Wow!
怎么画面变黄色了？
So, like, when did you get cable?
好啊，他说比萨饼可以免费
This is great. Gus says he'll let us have the pizzas for nothing...
太好了!
All right!
如果他能带几个人过来的话
...if he and a couple of friends can stop by after work.
几个？人多了恐怕.
Yo, how many? Because I don't think we should...
-有妞呢 -好!
- He mentioned women. - All right!
这次旅行真有意思
Is the rest of the trip going to be this much fun?
凯罗，带本去外公的房间看电视吧
Carol, why don't you and Ben go watch TV in Grandpa's den?
好的!
Great!
你当然好了，有我陪你
Sure, it's great for you. You get to spend time with me.
本，别碰外公的警察装备
Ben, don't you go touching any of your grandpa's police stuff.
放心好了
You know me.
杰森，我们要帮他们
Jason, we've got to help them.
但是你爸不要我们帮
I'm not so sure your dad wants our help.
话说回来，我算什么？ 我只是个江湖郎中
Then again, what do I know? I'm just a licensed quack.
-杰森 -不许动!
- Oh, Jason. - Freeze, slimebag!
爸爸？
Daddy?
埃德，差点打着杰森了
Ed, you almost shot Jason.
他们不该在这里出现
Well, they're not supposed to be here.
我是说这里应该没人的
No one's supposed to be here.
妈妈，还好吗？看到你真高兴
Mom, how are you? It's so good to see you.
我很好
I'm fine.
是不是你们说了要来，但我忘了？
Did you say you were coming, and I forgot?
-妈，没有 -埃德，幸会
- No, Mom, no. - Ed, always a pleasure to see you.
爸爸，爸爸!
Daddy, Daddy, Daddy!
小可爱!
Pumpkin!
你怎么要卖房子了？
So, what's this about selling the house?
这个.
Well...
我们打算过点退休的生活
we thought we'd do this retirement thing right.
搬到小一点的地方去住
Move into a smaller place with less upkeep.
住公寓
A condo.
-爷爷!奶奶! -凯罗，宝贝!
- Grandma! Grandpa! - Carol, honey!
长这么大了!
Look how she's grown.
小麦克呢？
Where's Mikey?
麦克没有来
Mike couldn't come.
爷爷!
Grandpa!
-是本吗？ -是的
- Is that Benny? - Yes.
小心
Look out.
举手投降出来吧
All right, come out with your hands up.
不行，凯罗把我铐在椅子上了
I can't. Carol handcuffed me to the chair.
把风，我去收拾他
Watch the door. I'm gonna rough him up.
抓到你了
Got you.
住手，等着瞧
Stop it. Wait till I get you.
本，我们去做饭吧
Well, we're going to fix a little dinner. Come on, Ben.
让爸爸跟外公聊聊
Let your dad and granddad talk.
-我看用不着了 -本就留下玩吧
- I don't think that'll be necessary. - No, he can play here.
本，跟其他犯人去削土豆
Come on, Ben. You can peel potatoes with the other prisoners.
Wow!
爸爸.
Daddy...
若是你们有经济困难，我们.
if you and Mom are having financial problems, we would be...
没有，经济很好
No. Things are swell.
一切安好，好极了
They're fine, even good.
不管需要多少钱，我和杰森.
Dad, any money you need, Jason and I would be more than happy to...
麦姬.
Maggie...
小姑娘，别忘了.
just in case you can't remember, little girl.
我不是有能力养了你18年吗？
I kept a roof over your head and food on the table for over 18 years.
直到他把你带走了
Till he came along, anyway.
爸爸
Daddy.
见鬼，我现在还能养活你妈妈和我自己
Damn it, I can still take care of your mom and myself...
不需要谁的施舍
without your charity!
埃德，埃德.
Ed, Ed, please...
你总不能因为对我有偏见而.
there's no reason for you to turn down this offer just because of...
-拒绝我们的帮助 -杰森，别提了
- how you feel about me. - Jason, let's not mention...
不，你爸爸应该不计前嫌.
No, no, no. Your dad should overcome his feelings about me...
保住这栋房子
and save this house.
干嘛为了这种盲目的自尊.
Why hurt your wife, your daughter, yourself...
而伤害老婆，女儿和自己？
all in the name of some foolish pride?
盲目？
Foolish?
别用江湖郎中那一套对待我
Don't use your shrink talk on me.
我是不会要你的钱的，除非我死了
The day I accept one dime of your money will be the day they bury me.
进行挺顺利的吧？
I think that went well, don't you?
杰里.
Yeah, Jerry, listen.
把布鲁斯叫来，罗宾路有派对
Call Bruce Vinaker. Tell him party central's at 15 Robin Hood Lane.
你是懒虫吗？
Excuse me, Slug, is it?
别再请人来了
I don't think we should invite any more people.
你是怎么了？你不知道？
Well, what's it to you? Didn't you hear?
那个大款的家人出城去了
The bozo that lives here? Parents are out of town.
-大款？你.. -麦克!
- Bozo? Hey, listen... - Hey, Mike!
记得我吗？我是琳达
Remember me? Lynda McManus!
记得一起学空手道吗？
We had a karate class together.
当然记得了，你的铁掌可厉害了
Yeah, yeah, of course I remember you. You have got killer hands.
-我的意思是.. -我懂你的意思
- I mean, I didn't mean... - I know what you mean.
麦克，过来
Mike, come here.
-失陪一分钟 -一分钟就好了
- Would you excuse me for just a second? - Okay. But just for a second.
埃迪!
Eddie!
里面有两个人在吐.
Michael, there are two guys out back throwing up...
楼上还有个家伙在刮毛
and a guy upstairs shaving.
这真是个无拘无束的派对
I mean, this has gotta be the coolest party I've ever been to.
刮毛？
Shaving?
麦克，给我几块钱 你妈妈的车子没油了
Mike, I need a couple of bucks. Your mom's car ran out of gas.
你不能用我妈妈的车
Eddie, you can't take my mom's car.
不是我，是弗兰克
I didn't. Frank did.
弗兰克是谁？
Who's Frank?
-我以为你认识他呢 -不认识
- I thought you knew him. - No.
送比萨那人的车子启动不了 所以他打电话叫弗兰克.
All right, Gus' pizzamobile wouldn't start, right? So he calls Frank...
要我们自己去取比萨
and says we'd have to pick up our own pizzas...
看在免费的份上，希望顺便送几趟货
and since they're free, could we make a couple of deliveries?
用我妈妈的车？
In my mom's car?
-弗兰克该怎么办？ -弗兰克.
- What was Frank supposed to do? - What was Frank...
弗兰克该怎么办？
What was Frank supposed to do?
好吧，没关系
All right. Relax, babe. It's under control.
你就给点油钱吧
Now, just give me a little gas money.
妈妈，让爸爸收钱吧 这房子你也有份
Mom, make Dad take the money. It's your home, too.
你爸爸说了算
Well, your father's the boss.
结婚当日我承诺过嫁夫随夫
And on our wedding day, I promised to love, honor and obey.
妈妈，妈妈.. “三从四德”对现代女性来说只是个词语
Mom, Mom, Mom, every modern woman knows "obey" is just a figure of speech.
所以才有这么多现代女性离婚
Maybe that's why every modern woman seems to get divorced.
凯特，孩子们围在钢琴边，等你弹奏呢
Kate, the kids are glued to the piano, they're waiting for one of your songs.
好呀，我弄到一首歌
Oh, good. I just got the sheet music to Like a Virgin.
其实他们是被铐在钢琴边
Actually, they're not glued, they're handcuffed.
杰森，我说服不了妈妈 要看咱们了，你怎么看？
Oh, Jason, I got nowhere with my mother. It's up to us. What are we going to do?
我怎么看？无计可施
What are we going to do? I don't have the slightest idea.
不能眼睁睁卖掉房子，无非是6千块
We can't let them lose their home. Jason, all they need is $6,000.
我们不是不愿、意给钱，有说错吗？
Well, correct me if I'm wrong. Didn't we just offer your father money?
一句“除非我死了”就让你放弃了？
And you're giving up just because he said he'd rather be dead?
-他这样我还能怎样？ -好吧
- Forgive me. What was I thinking? - That's better. Okay.
你有什么计划？
So, what's your plan?
我没有计划
I don't have a plan.
没有计划就行动是不明智的
Do you think it's wise to proceed without a plan?
-这歌刚放过 -好了啦
- We just heard this record. - That's okay.
乐队马上就来了
The band should be here any minute.
邦纳，场面失去控制了
Boner, this party is completely out of control.
知道了，恭喜你
I know, man. Congratulations.
我得想想办法 但不能让人觉得我胆小
No, man, I gotta do something about it without everybody thinking I'm a wimp.
麦克，别急，今晚要破派对记录了
Relax, Mikey. Tonight, you're making party history.
Hey!
老兄!
Hey, bud!
不好意思，请把这个给我
Excuse me, Slug. Mind if I cut in?
我死定了
I'm a dead man.
至少我风流过15年
At least I was cool for 15 years.
警察局？我是.
Hello, police? Yeah. This is...
我是甘地先生
Mr. Gandhi. Yes, Bob Gandhi.
我现在住在罗宾路，我热爱和平
Yes, I am a very peace-loving man, and I am living on Robin Hood Lane.
这附近一向清静
Yes, it is normally a very peaceful street.
今晚15号那里却闹翻天了
But tonight there is a very, very loud party at Number 15.
对，就是西弗家
Yes, it is, I believe, the Seaver home.
真是难以置信.
Yes, this is very hard to believe...
他们家一向很和睦
since they are such a loving, peaceful family.
是的，请好好对待西弗家 那个叫麦克的孩子
Yes. And please be going easy on the Seaver boy called Mike.
他很老实.
He is a very, very spiritual boy...
这绝对兴他无关
and none of this could possibly be his fault.
还是忙音，麦克打给谁了呢？
Still busy. I wonder who Mike could be talking to.
妈，到你了
Mom, come and take your turn.
-对 -我这姿势对吗？
- Yeah. - Am I doing this right?
-他在房间里？ -对
- Is he in his den? - Yeah.
好吧，麦姬，是你叫我想出计划来的
Okay, Maggie. You're the one who wanted me to come up with a plan.
你打算怎样？
What are you going to do?
不知道
I have no idea.
埃德？
Ed?
又来“大发慈悲”了？
Come to make another generous offer, did you?
你又来“心领了”？
Ready with another gracious turndown?
我不是要施舍什么，我是来道歉的
No, I didn't come to offer you anything, Ed, except an apology.
拿着
Here.
爱尔兰威士忌？
Irish whiskey?
若是给你钱.
Well, you know, I thought that maybe deep down...
我内心深处确实有点沾沾自喜
I really did want to embarrass you a little when I offered you that money.
这点我承认
I admit that.
对不起
I'm sorry.
坐下
Sit down.
-拿杯子来 -好的
- Grab a couple of glasses there. - Okay.
象棋？
Game of checkers?
好啊
Sure.
要调酒吗？
How're we going to get any ginger ale in these?
调酒？这是爱尔兰威士忌
Ginger ale? That's Irish, man.
-直接喝太呛了 -暴殄天物
- I know you can't drink that straight. - Blasphemy.
-口气不小 -不信你看
- Big talk. - Well, you just watch.
才这么一小口
One sip. Big deal.
我打赌你喝不完
Bet you can't drain that.
你看着吧
Keep watching.
来吧
You're on.
-100块 -这算什么
- $100. - Well, can't be that tough.
赌双倍我也行
Double or nothing says I can do it.
你？
You?
赌吧
You're on.
我又赢了
I won again.
你要给机会我回本
Well, you have to give me a chance to get even.
-本，凯罗 -“上床”
- Ben, Carol... - "Go to bed."
对
Right.
警察怎么还不来？
Where are the cops? Where are the cops?
在这里跳舞不够宽敞
We need more room to dance.
咱把家具搬到厨房
Let's shove all the furniture into the kitchen.
好啊
Yeah.
麦克，叫你妈妈检查一下刹车
Michael, tell your mother she should have her brakes checked.
弗兰克在后座睡了 事先声明，他吐了，我没有
Oh, Frank's asleep in the back seat. And for the record, he puked, not me.
-比萨! -太棒了
- Pizza! - Yeah.
够了!
All right, that's it.
警察不来，派对也要结束了
Cops or no cops, this party is over.
这下完了
Just like my life.
食物炮弹!
Food fight!
大家够了!
Hey, hey! Come on, people!
够了!住手!
Come on! Hey, stop!
我是麦克，这里的主人 我有话要说
Hey, I'm Mike. I'm the bozo giving this party. I got something to say.
装模作样
Big deal.
Hey!
-麦克，做人要厚道 -我不管
- Hey, Mike, yo, this is not cool. - I don't care.
我告诉你们，特别是你，懒虫.
I want all of you people, especially you, Slug, to just...
警察!开门!
Open up! Police!
谁那么孬种叫警察了？
Oh, nice. Nice. All right, now, who called the police?
派对正要进入高潮
Come on, this party was just starting to cook.
天哪!
God!
不行了，大叔
No, that's it. Uncle.
最后一次还是输给你了
Beaten me for the last time, Ed.
据我记录，你一共输了7次
By my records, you lost seven times.
双倍的双倍，开始是100
Let's see. That's double or nothing, starting at $100.
对
Right.
共6400元
32, $6,400.
1变成2，4，8，16，32
So you owe me... The 1 goes to 2, that's 4, 8, 16...
$6,400?
6400？
什么？
What?
是这么多，我也搞不懂
That's what it comes to. I don't get it, either.
你当然不懂了
Oh, sure you don't, Ed.
-我服了你了 -这是怎么了？
- No, nice job, you got me. - How did I do that?
我才喝了3杯，不过你一杯也没喝完
I only had three shots. You never got all the way through one of yours.
你自以为比心理医生聪明吗？
So, Big Ed finally shows the overpaid psychiatrist just who's smarter.
我可不认这个帐
I don't like to be taken, Ed.
我骗你了？
I didn't take you.
-我赢得光明正大 -我不给钱
- I won that fair and square. - Well, I'm not paying.
我看你不给!拿钱来!
The hell you're not! I want my money!
怎么了？
Well?
不给6400块，别想出这门
Jason, you're not leaving this house until I get my $6,400.
埃德.
Eddie...
我们保住了房子，也保住了名誉
we get to keep our house, and you get to keep your pride.
我早说过我能照顾你
Hey, I told you I'd take care of you, didn't I?
-谢谢你，亲爱的 -刚输了6000大洋
- Thank you, honey. - Hey, I just lost $6,000...
看来饭也吃不成了
and I may lose my lunch.
我就知道你能照顾我
I knew you'd take care of me.
警官，谢谢你们 下面我来处理吧
Thanks for your help, Officer. I can handle it from here.
太客气了，甘地先生
You are very, very welcome, Mr. Gandhi.
爸爸妈妈，欢迎回家!
Welcome home, Mom and Dad!
让开!人有三急!
Out of my way! Nature calls!
麦克，周末好玩吗？
Well, Mike. How was your weekend?
过得很无聊
Oh, kind of boring.
你们在外公外婆家好玩吗？
How was your weekend with Grandma and Grandpa?
不错，不错
Oh, fine, fine.
你爸爸是本周英雄呢
Actually, your father was a hero this weekend.
救了一栋房子
He saved a house.
真的？
Oh, really?
-太巧了 -什么？
- What a coincidence. - What?
你们在远方.
You know, it's just nice to know that you guys were up there...
我在这里.
I was down here and...
都很好
Hey, it's a wonderful world.
你还在浇粪？
I thought your manure-spreading job was over yesterday.
哪来的狗？
What dog?
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.04.01